A Guide to the American Chemical Society Virginia Section records, 1927-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
American Chemical Society Virginia Section records, 1927-2001
The Library of Virginia
30462
12.3 cu. ft. and 34 boxes
American Chemical Society Virginia section
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the American Chemical Society, 1979, 1981, and 2001
Custodial History
Accessions 31213 and 38302 are interfiled with accession 30462.
Historical Information
The American Chemical Society was founded 6 April 1876 at the College of Pharmacy of the City of New York. The society established its flagship journal, T he Journal of the American Chemical Society in April 1879. The American Chemical Society is the world's largest scientific society. The Virginia Section of the American Chemical Society was chartered 9 April 1915 and covers northern and central Virginia. It works to further education in chemistry.
Scope and Content
Records, 1927-2001, of the American Chemical Society Virginia Section consisting of articles, clippings, correspondence, financial records, lectures, minutes, newsletters, pamphlets, photographs, research papers, reports, and other papers relating to the operations and goals of the Virginia Section and of the American Chemical Society.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Chairman's files, 1944-1961.
Series II: Vice Chairman's files, 1939-1948, 1958.
Series III: Secretary's files, 1934-1959, 1975.
Series IV: Treasurer's files, 1927-1963.
Series V: Program Chairman and Committee files, 1942-1961.
Series VI: Executive Committee files, 1941-2001 (intermittent).
Series VII: Committee files, 1942-1949, 1960-1967.
Series VIII: General files, 1932-2001.
Contents List
- Series I: Chairman's files, 1944-1961., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 1-5)
  Series I: Chairman's files, 1944-1961, includes articles, correspondence, financial papers, minutes, pamphlets, reports, and other records regarding the national organization, chemistry research, committees, councillors and trustees, education, membership, secretary and treasurer, section meetings, and other matters.
  - Committees, 1944-1945. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Councillors and trustees, 1944-1945. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General correspondence, 1944-1945. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Secretary and treasurer, 1944-1945. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer file, 1945-1946. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chairman, American Chemical Society, 1946-1947. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chairman, American Chemical Society, 1947-1948. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Committees, 1955 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committees, 1955 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - National office, 1954. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National office, 1955. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New officers, 1955. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1955. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chairman's file, 1956 (folder 1 of 3). (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chairman's file, 1956 (folder 2 of 3). (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chairman's file, 1956 (folder 3 of 3). (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chairman's file, 1957 (folder 1 of 4). (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chairman's file, 1957 (folder 2 of 4). (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chairman's file, 1957 (folder 3 of 4). (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chairman's file, 1957 (folder 4 of 4). (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chairman's file, 1958 (folder 1 of 4). (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chairman's file, 1958 (folder 2 of 4). (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chairman's file, 1958 (folder 3 of 4). (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chairman's file, 1958 (folder 4 of 4). (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chairman's file, 1959 (folder 1 of 4). (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chairman's file, 1959 (folder 2 of 4). (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chairman's file, 1959 (folder 3 of 4). (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chairman's file, 1959 (folder 4 of 4). (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chairman's file, 1960 (folder 1 of 4). (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chairman's file, 1960 (folder 2 of 4). (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chairman's file, 1960 (folder 3 of 4). (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chairman's file, 1960 (folder 4 of 4). (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chairman's file, 1961 (folder 1 of 4). (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Chairman's file, 1961 (folder 2 of 4). (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chairman's file, 1961 (folder 3 of 4). (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chairman's file, 1961 (folder 4 of 4). (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series II: Vice Chairman's files, 1939-1948, 1955., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 5-6)
  Series II: Vice Chairman's files, 1939-1948, 1955, contain correspondence, minutes, reports, and other records regarding lectures, programs, and the Virginia Section of the American Chemical Society.
  - Correspondence, 1939. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January-May 1940. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1940. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, January-March 1941. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, April-December 1941. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, January-September 1942. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, October 1942-1943. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, June 1945-April 1946. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, May 1946-May 1947. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1947-1948. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Records, 1955. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series III: Secretary's files, 1934-1959, 1975., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 6-12)
  Series III: Secretary's files, 1934-1959, 1975, contains agendas, by-laws, clippings, constitutions, correspondence, financial records, lists, magazines, memorandums, minutes, newsletters, photographs, reports, and other records concerning the operations of the Virginia Section including the executive committee, membership, and programs, as well as the section's relationship with the national organization.
  - Annual reports, 1938-1950. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1937, 1940. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1941. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1941. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, January-May 1942. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1942. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1943. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1944. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1945. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1946. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1947. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1949. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, May-August 1949. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1949. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1950. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1952. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1953. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, February 1954. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, August-November 1954. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Secretary's file, 1947-1948 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Secretary's file, 1947-1948 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Secretary's file, 1950-1951 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Secretary's file, 1950-1951 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Secretary's file, 1951-1952. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Secretary's file, 1952-1953. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Secretary's file, 1953-1955 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Secretary's file, 1953-1955 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Secretary's file, 1955 (folder 1 of 3). (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Secretary's file, 1955 (folder 2 of 3). (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Secretary's file, 1955 (folder 3 of 3). (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Records of the secretary, 1956 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Records of the secretary, 1956 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Records of the secretary, 1957 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Records of the secretary, 1957 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Records of the secretary, 1959 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Records of the secretary, 1959 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Local Section Chats (newsletter), 1943-1950. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - [Membership] lists, 1940-1942. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Associate membership lists, 1940, 1947-1950. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - New associate members, 1941-1942. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Membership, 1945-1950. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Membership committee, 1947-1948. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1948-1949. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of meetings of Virginia Section, 1934-1947. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of meetings of the Virginia Section, 1947-1950. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1936-1950. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Schedule and minutes of council meeting and report of the executive secretary of the American Chemical Society, 1948. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - American Chemical Society building dedication brochure, 1960. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Secretary's file, 1975. (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Treasurer's files, 1927-1963., Extent: 6 boxes. (Box 12-17)
  Series IV: Treasurer's files, 1927-1963, include bank statements, correspondence, journals, receipts, reports, tax returns, and other records regarding the financial status of the Virginia Section and its programs and operations.
  - Cash receipts and disbursements journal, 1927-1945. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Cash receipts and disbursements journal, 1945-1948. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Authorization for expenditures, 1947-1948. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Records of the treasurer, 1948-1949. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Financial records, 1949-1950. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer's records, 1950-1951. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer's records, 1951-1952. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's records, 1952-1953. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer's records, 1953-1954 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's records, 1953-1954 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer's records, 1955. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer's records, 1956. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer's records, 1957. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's records, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer's records, 1959. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's records, 1960 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer's records, 1960 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer's records, 1961 (folder 1 of 3). (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer's records, 1961 (folder 2 of 3). (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's records, 1961 (folder 3 of 3). (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Financial reports, 1962-1963. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1938. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1939. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1940. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, January-July 1941. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, August-December 1941. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, January-May 1942. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1942. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1943. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, January-July 1944. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1944. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: checks, financial records, 1943-1944. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1945. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1947. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1948. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1949. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Committee on entertainment and attendance, 1944-1947. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, bills, bank statements, and checks, 1941-1950 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Receipts, bills, bank statements, and checks, 1941-1950 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Series V: Program Chairman and Committee files, 1942-1961., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 18-21)
  Series V: Program Chairman and Committee files, 1942-1961, includes biographies, clippings, correspondence, lectures, photographs, schedules, and other records concerning the scheduling and delivery of lectures and talks for the Virginia section.
  - Correspondence, August 1942-August 1943. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1943. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, January-July 1944. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, August-December 1944. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1945. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1946. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January-July 1947. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, August-December 1947. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January-August 1948. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1948. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1949. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1951. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1952. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January-August 1953. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1953. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, January-March 1954. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, April-December 1954. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1955. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Papers, 1955. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Papers, 1956. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Papers, 1957. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Papers, 1958. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Papers, 1959. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Papers, 1960. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Papers, 1960-1961. (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Series VI: Executive Committee files, 1941-1942, 1961-1964, 1971-1976, 1980, 1985-2001., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 21-23)
  Series VI: Executive Committee files, 1941-1942, 1961-1964, 1971-1976, 1980, 1985-2001, consists of correspondence, financial records, minutes, reports, rosters, and other records of the executive committee concerning the goals and operations of the Virginia Section of the American Chemical Society, including membership, program, and committees.
  - Meeting minutes, 1941-1942. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Papers, 1961. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Papers, 1962. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Papers, 1963. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Papers, 1964. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Annual reports, 1972-1975. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Financial reports, 1972-1976. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1973-1976. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Rosters, 1973-1976. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Awards for outstanding chemists, report; division and section awards, 1974-1976. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Publicity committee, 1971-1975. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Program committee, 1972-1975. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Membership activities department, 1973-1974. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Entertainment committee reports, 1972-1973. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Nominating committee, 1974-1976. (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Education and manpower committee, 1975-1976. (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Meetings, 1980. (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Meetings, 1985. (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Meetings, 1986. (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Meetings, 1987. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Meetings, 1988. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Meetings, 1989. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Meetings, 1990. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Meetings, 1991. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Meetings, 1992. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Meetings, 1993. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Meetings, 1994. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Meetings, 1995. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Meetings, 1996. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Meetings, 1997. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Meetings, 1999. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Meetings, 2000. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Meetings, 2001. (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Series VII: Committee files, 1942-1949, 1960-1967., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 23-25)
  Series VII: Committee files, 1942-1949, 1953-1954, 1960-1967, contains ballots, catalogs, clippings, correspondence, financial records, lists, manuals, pamphlets, publications, reports, and other records regarding the operations of the various committees of the Virginia Section of the American Chemical Society.
  - Auditing committee, 1963. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Awards committee, 1962-1963. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Chemical defense committee, 1942-1943. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Education and manpower committee, 1962-1963. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Employment committee, 1962-1963. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Entertainment committee, 1962. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Hospitality committee, 1962. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Membership committee, 1962-1963. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Nominating committee, 1943, 1945, 1947. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Nominating committee, 1960-1964. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Program committee, 1962-1963. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Program committee, 1964. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Program committee, 1965. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Program committee, 1966-1967. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Publicity committee, 1947-1949. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Publicity committee, 1953-1954. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Publicity committee, 1962-1963. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Radio and t.v. committee, 1960, 1962-1963. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Research committee, 1942 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Research committee, 1942 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Committees, 1942-1944. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Committees, 1945-1946. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Committees, 1948-1949. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Committees, 1962. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Committees, January-July 1963. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Committees, August-October 1963. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Committees, November-December 1963. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Committees, 1964-1965. (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Series VIII: General files, 1932-2001., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 25-34)
  Series VIII: General files, 1932-2001, consists of articles, awards, ballots, biographies, booklets, by-laws, certificates, charters, constitutions, correspondence, financial records, histories, legislation, manuals, minutes, newsletters, notes, papers, reports, rosters, and other records concerning structure of the Virginia Section and the national organization; membership; elections; programs; speakers; education; research; national, regional, and section meetings; chemical defense; radio; and other aspects and interests of the Virginia Section of the American Chemical Society. The newsletters are Local Section Chat and the Bulletin.
  - Constitution and by-laws (American Chemical Society and Virginia Section), 1945. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Constitution and by-laws (American Chemical Society and Virginia Section), 1945, 1947. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Constitution and by-laws (American Chemical Society and Virginia Section), 1959. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Charter, constitution, and by-laws of the American Chemical Society, 1974-1980. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - By-laws of the Virginia Section, 1977. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - By-laws of the Virginia Section, 1985. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - By-laws of the Virginia Section, 1999. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Job manual for Virginia Section, 1957. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Job manual for Virginia Section, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Job manual for Virginia Section, 1981. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Expenditures, 1962. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Expenditures, 1963. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Expenditures, 1964-1965. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Local sections activities reports, 1954. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Local sections activities reports, 1955. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Reports of committees and officers, 1964. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Year end reports, 1964-1965. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Annual reports, 1975 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Annual reports, 1975 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Reports, 1978-1979. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Annual report, 1985. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Annual report, 1986. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Annual report, 1987. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Annual report, 1988. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Annual report, 1989. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Annual report, 1993. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Annual report, 1994. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, January-September 1933. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, October-December 1933. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1934. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1935. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1938. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1942. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, February-July 1943. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, August-December 1943. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1944. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1945. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1946. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1947, 1940s no year. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1959. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1961. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, January-February 1962. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, March-May 1962. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, June-August 1962. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, September-October 1962. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, November-December 1962. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1963. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1964. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, July-December, no month 1964. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1965. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, January-February 1966. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, March-April 1966. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, May-June 1966. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, July-September 1966. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, October-December 1966. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1974. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1975. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January-May 1976. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1976. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1977. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1980. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1986. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1987. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1988. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1989. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1992. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1993. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1997. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Elections, 1987. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Elections, 1988. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Elections, 1989. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Elections, 1994. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Elections, 1995. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Elections, 1997. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Elections, 1999. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Speakers, 1941. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Speakers, 1941-1942. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Speakers, 1945-1946. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Speakers, 1961. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Local Section Chats (newsletters), 1944. (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Local Section Chats (newsletters), 1945. (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Local Section Chats (newsletters), 1946. (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Local Section Chats (newsletters), 1947. (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1973-1974. (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1976-1977. (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1987. (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1988. (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1989. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1990. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1991. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1992. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1993. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1994. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1995. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1996. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1997. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1998. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 1999. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 2000. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - The Bulletin (newsletters), 2001. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Charter, Constitution, Bylaws, and Regulations of the American Chemical Society and Charter, Constitution, Bylaws, and Regulations of the American Chemical Society, 1961, 1964. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Charter, Constitution, Bylaws, and Regulations of the American Chemical Society (2 copies), 1963. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Handbook for Councilors, 1964. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Information for Local Section Officers, 1948, 1956, 1963, 1964. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Handbook for Local Section Membership Committees, 1961, 1963. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - A Guide for Secretaries, 1964. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Guide to Special Meetings, 1957. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Local Section Activities, 1950, 1976. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Directories, 1976, 1980. (Box 32, Folder 6)